<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PowerShell on Saggie Haim - Automate Everything</title>
    <link>//localhost:8080/categories/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PowerShell on Saggie Haim - Automate Everything</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</webMaster>
    <copyright>Saggie Haim</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:8080/categories/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Connect to Azure With Powershell</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/how-to-connect-to-azure-with-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/how-to-connect-to-azure-with-powershell/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell is the Automator&amp;rsquo;s best friend. I automate everything with PowerShell, and you can also. When it comes to Azure, I can&amp;rsquo;t remember the last time I created a resource in the Portal. I either use PowerShell or IaC to provision resources or modify them.&#xA;In this post, you will learn how to set up a session with Azure to start to interact with Azure Resources.&#xA;Prerequisites Before we start, there are few global prerequisites that you need to meet:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Install Powershell 7 on Wsl and Ubuntu</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/install-powershell-7-on-wsl-and-ubuntu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/install-powershell-7-on-wsl-and-ubuntu/</guid>
      <description>With PowerShell 7, we get the best PowerShell edition, most importantly, it’s cross-platform! While last time we installed the latest PowerShell 7 on a container, sometimes we don’t want just a plain environment with PowerShell, sometimes we want a to add other tools, change system configurations or use different Linux Distros.&#xA;That is why we use WSL.&#xA;What is WSL? WSL or Windows Subsystem for Linux is a feature that lets us run full Linux distributions on top of our Windows OS without the overhead of running virtualization tools.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Background Jobs Start Threadjob vs Start Job</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/background-jobs-start-threadjob-vs-start-job/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/background-jobs-start-threadjob-vs-start-job/</guid>
      <description>PowerShell can run background jobs with the Start-Job cmdlet. Most of the cmdlet also have -AsJob switch to instantly run the cmdlet as a background job. Each job runs a cmdlet in the background without interacting with the current session. This gives us the ability to perform an action on many targets quicker. This also come with some “downsides”, it’s resource consuming (depend on how many tasks running in the background) as each job is a separated process.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Running Powershell Core in a Container</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/running-powershell-core-in-a-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/running-powershell-core-in-a-container/</guid>
      <description>With Powershell V7 on the verge, the importance of building solutions that are cross-platforms in Powershell is bigger. One of the issues we have while running tests, is that our Powershell environment is not “clean” as in other computers. That’s where Powershell Core in a container gets in the picture.&#xA;We install a lot of modules, software and other things that our target audience or servers won’t share. Our solution could act differently in those environments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Build Gui for Powershell</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/build-gui-for-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/build-gui-for-powershell/</guid>
      <description>Hey everyone! Today I want to talk about GUI for PowerShell. You probably wonder why? PowerShell is all about the CLI and moving away from the GUI. but sometimes, a GUI for our scripts can be very useful.&#xA;Every Company has HelpDesk team, other System Admins that don’t know PowerShell at all, or non-technical staff. While I will encourage them to learn, I can’t make them. As a result, I need to provide them with a GUI for some of the tools or solutions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sorting Group Policy</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/sorting-group-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/sorting-group-policy/</guid>
      <description>So, this is the first post for 2019! Happy new year!Today I want to talk about a painful topic, the Group Policy. It’s almost the same in every company. it’s historical, contain a lot of Group Policy and if you ever try to touch it, half of the systems stop working.&#xA;Its ok burning meme Last week I saw a post from my good friend Omer a Microsoft PFE, as he talked about Common Mistakes in Active Directory and Domain Services .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Updating Sharepoint Online List With Powershell the Easy Way</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/updating-sharepoint-online-list-with-powershell-the-easy-way/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/updating-sharepoint-online-list-with-powershell-the-easy-way/</guid>
      <description>Hey Guys! It’s been a long time since my last post, as I been busy with work trips. But now I’m back! And I want to share with you my experience with PowerShell and SharePoint Online. To be honest, I never worked with SharePoint before. I got a request from the SharePoint team to update a list weekly from a CSV report that HR provides (Weekly employees birthdays, nothing exciting).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>PowerShell History</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/powershell-history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/powershell-history/</guid>
      <description>Howdy folks! How are you today?&#xA;After my last post, I had to prepare for my trip to the USA, had to visit two of our offices and set up a new one. Unfortunately, the big California fire started… so things ware little tense during my stay, hope everyone is safe over there!&#xA;While working there, my colleague asks me about some cmdlets I ran in the last site we visited.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Create Vmware Snapshots Report</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/create-vmware-snapshots-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/create-vmware-snapshots-report/</guid>
      <description>Konichiwa Yujin,&#xA;Sorry for not posting for so long, I been to Japan for a work trip. While Japan is amazing, the state of the ESXi in the office wasn’t so great. The ESXi crushed, and after investigation, we notice that he had no free space on HDD’s, which was weird. we have 100TB, and only 4 VM’s. the first suspect? Snapshots!&#xA;Japanese Garden building&#xA;Snapshots are great, but they can be your worst enemy if you don’t use them correctly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Assessing New Domain Environment</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/assessing-new-domain-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/assessing-new-domain-environment/</guid>
      <description>I had a free day yesterday, and I always love to spend my free time on the Xbox or PlayStation, depends on the mood. So, while I’m rushing and jumping all over Australia with my Lamborghini, I got a phone call, my first instinct was to mute it and continue with my race, but it was a good friend&amp;hellip; so I muted it anyway 😶. When I finished the race, I called him back (yes, I’m a good friend😜).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Update Powershell Help Background</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/update-powershell-help-background/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/update-powershell-help-background/</guid>
      <description>The help system in PowerShell is great. I think it&amp;rsquo;s the first thing everyone should master before they jump into PowerShell. By default, PowerShell ships without the help files, so first you have to update the PowerShell help database to unlock its power. Over the time, you will collect more modules and updates, so keeping it up to date is a challenge.&#xA;Image PowerShell terminal running Get-Help&#xA;When you run PowerShell in a new computer, and try to use the Get-Help cmdlet, PowerShell will ask you if you want to update help first, if you choose not to, the help you will get will be very limited.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ditch Cmd for Powershell</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/ditch-cmd-for-powershell/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/ditch-cmd-for-powershell/</guid>
      <description>When I started to learn PowerShell, I said to myself “I’m going to do everything in PowerShell”. In the beginning, the simpler stuff like unlocking a locked-out account, or resetting a password, took me 5 minutes. I had to google how to do it on PowerShell, understand what I’m reading and testing it before I’m deleting all organization users.&#xA;With the practice and learning, things become much better and most important, faster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating Powershell Profile</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/creating-powershell-profile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/creating-powershell-profile/</guid>
      <description>I had a conversation with a friend today, talked about work, he told me that he has some scripts that he uses a lot in his day-to-day job, and thought about creating a script that loads all of them at once. The first thing I told him is “Why don’t you set up a profile?” he waited for a few seconds and told me that he doesn’t know about profiles. If you are reading this and feel the same, this post is for you 🙂 PowerShell profile is a script that runs every time we start the shell.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Automating The Network Redesign Process</title>
      <link>//localhost:8080/posts/automation-network-redesign/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>contact@saggiehaim.net (Saggie Haim)</author>
      <guid>//localhost:8080/posts/automation-network-redesign/</guid>
      <description>Namaste! I’m sitting in my hotel room, it’s very late, hoping not to get sick. It’s my first day in India, as my company has an office here in New Delhi. If you wonder why I hope not to get sick, well, this was my dinner today:&#xA;Image of my indian dinner&#xA;To be honest, it was very nice, not the best I had, but far from my worst one. If you didn’t notice, it had chicken inside.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
